Advanced web developer with over <u>6 years of experience</u> in structuring, developing and implementing interactive websites. Excellent communication skills and ability to work independently/team. Perform well within cross-functional teams. Able to meet stipulated deadlines. Self-motivated, highly committed to responsibilities.

SKILLS

PHP	Javascript	CSS	Databases	Other
Symfony 2/3/4	React 15/16	LESS/SASS/SCSS	MySQL	Docker
Laravel	MobX	Bootstrap 3/4	Oracle	ScotchBox
Code Ignitor	Redux	Foundation	MongoDB	Linux
Kohana	Reactstrap	Materialize	Memcache	AWS
Magento	Handlebars			Jira
	D3			Bamboo
	Puppeteer			Bitbucket
	WebGL			Confluence
	Webpack			
	Babel			
	JQuery			

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER, AMBRY GENETICS A KONICA MINOLTA COMPANY

(MAY 2016 - NOW)

- Migrated assigned projects and libraries from Symfony 2 to Symfony 4.
- Refactored assigned project that allowed upgrade php from 5.6 to 7.2 (Symfony 2 and Kohana 2 projects).
- Dockerized and configured Docker swarm for assigned projects.
 (Frontend React, Backend Symfony API, Image generation Node, Databases Mongo).
- Configured automatic deployment for dockerized assigned projects and docker stacks using Bamboo.
- Developed report generation tool using React (MobX State Tree) and Handlebars libraries on frontend and php (Symfony 4)/ Perl on a backend, that allowed clinicians configure and generate any report and report templates.
- Developed Image generation tool, and other various DNA related images using Node, D3, and WebGL and configured builds environments using webpack and babel.
- Managed team of 4 people that included QAs BA and 2 developer for assigned projects.
- Organized backlog into sprints, ran scrum ceremonies, handled deployments for assigned project using **Jira**, **Bitbucket**, **Bamboo**.
- Organized and configured **automation testing** for assigned projects using **puppeteer.js** library to mimic Chrome.

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER, CLOUDMARKETING INC (JAN 2016 – MAY 2016 – CONTRACT)

- Migrated existing code to allow upgrade **php** from **5.2** to **5.6**.
- Designed custom framework with a help of **Symphony** libraries to handle legacy code, but be scalable and easy to maintain using **php** and **JavaScript** (**jQuery**, **bootstrap**).
- Migrated existing **php** front end script into **React single page application** using **Redux** for state management.
- Designed and developed custom sales boards for sales team using React and D3.
- Integrated new framework with various CRM systems using **php/Perl** scripts.
- Configured automated jobs for scraping data from google, Facebook for marketing purposes using **php**.
- Maintained Oracle and MySQL databases of existing leads. (1000 GB of data).
- Participated on code reviews, unit test and documentation reviews, in team meeting to help improve development process.
- Organized all **code documentation** to allow easy knowledge transfer of existing code base to outsourced developers.

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER, AIRSOFT MEGASTORE (JUNE 2015 – JAN 2016)

- Designed and Developed API platform using **CodeIgnitor** (**php**) to support existing outsourced .asp e-commerce platform.
- Designed and developer gun builder/gun customer feature using **jQuery, SVG** and organized build process to support frontend using **php** scripts in **CodeIgnitor** framework.
- Developed various scripts using **php/python** to help automate various tasks in warehouse.
- Developed webshot system using **php** and front end plugins using **js (jQuery)** on a front end to help marketing needs.
- Developed crawlers using php/python scripts.
- Handled migration data from existing .asp e-commerce platform into Magento, designed and developed various plugins and themes for Magento e-commerce platform.
- Developed and organized daily sync to new platform until migrated was completed using **php** cron job and **RabbitMQ** messaging system.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER III, VIBE MEDIA INC. (2012 – June 2015)

- Organized automated web scraping system using php scripts and AWS.
- Organized automated messaging system using php script for marketing needs.
- Maintained existing custom **php** framework and **jQuery** frontend.
- Handled technical troubleshooting within an enterprise environment, including system crashes, slow-downs, data recoveries.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, MAGIC APPLIANCE INC. (2011–2012)

EDUCATION

- Pierce College Computer Science major.
- Valley College Computer Science major.
- Belarusian State University informatics and Radio electronics (Artificial Intelligence Major)

2